Finding Aid for the Tulancingo (Hildago, Mexico) Manuscript Collection, 1567-1882 LSC.2073
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Post-1852 manuscripts, 1854-1877; 5 boxes
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos promovido por el Ciud. Agustin Cosio contra el de igual clase Vic[en]te Ramir[e]z, 1869; 4 leaves (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Verbal judgment in a financial dispute in the entitled action Agustin Cosio versus Vicente Ramirez. File includes the petition and letter for receipt of payment pursuant to the judgment found in favor of Agustín Cosio.
  - El Ciudadano Trinidad Cásares solicitando se le dé testimonio de unos exhÓrlos relativos á la posecion que se diÓ de la hacienda de Tecanecapa, 1869; 7 leaves (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Civil suit in a property dispute involving a ranch in Tecanecapa.
  - José Antonio Martinez promovido juicio de divorcio a su esposa D[oñ]a Emilia Barredo, 1869-1870; 24 leaves (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Judgment for divorce involving José Antonio Martinez and Doña Emilia Barredo. Petition and legal documents reveal that the couple had four children during their fourteen years of marriage and that Don Martinez alleged that his wife had an affair.
  - [Petitions and legal documents pertaining to the estate of Don José Flor and the executorship of Don Luís Pasos Nieto], 1869; 32 leaves (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Probate documents pertaining to the estate of Don José Flor and the administration of the estate by Don Luís Pasos Nieto. Documents indicate decedent left behind a widow, Doña Gertrudis Soto, and heirs Macario, Dolores, María de Jesus, and María Ysabel.
  - Promobido por D[on] Luís Pasos Nieto renunciando el albaceasgo de la testamentaría de D[on] José Flor, 1869; 24 leaves (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Inventory of debts and expenditures pertaining to the estate of Don José Flor submitted by Don Luís Pasos Nieto, executor. Various petitions and legal documents pertaining to the administration of the estate, including one by Macario Flor, son of decedent.
  - [Petitions and legal documents concerning a debt owed by Don José Haro to Don Juan Olavarrieta, a merchant, for a mortgage on an iron foundry], 1869; 9 leaves (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Petitions and legal documents concerning a debt owed by Don José Haro to Don Juan Olavarrieta, a merchant, for a mortgage on an iron foundry.
  - [Will and testament of Doña María Ygnacia Alarcon de Olvera], 1869; 7 leaves (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Will and testament of Doña Maria Ygnacia Alarcon de Olvera which lists Don Antonio Olvera executor of the estate and includes an itemized inventory of assets to be distributed among the following heirs: José María, María de la Soledad, María Rafaela.
  - Juicio ejecutivo promovido sobre pesos por el Ciudadano Rafaél Yslas contra el de igual da se Rafaél Várgas, 1868-1869; 29 leaves (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Executive judgment in a financial dispute involving Rafael Yslas and Rafael Várgas y Muños. Documents indicate a dispute over an outstanding lien for a house in Metepec. Folder also contains the related arbitration file.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos: D[on] José Vicente Moreno contra la S[eño]ra D[oñ]a Petra Oliva de Moreno, 1870; 28 leaves (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Petition and judgment ordering Doña Petra Oliva de Moreno to pay Don José Vicente Morena three hundred pesos and court costs. A related issue is a loan which Doña Petra Oliva de Moreno had arranged from Don Antonio Gayol.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos promovido por Doñ[a] Trinidad Campos contra Don Nestor Garzon, Concluído., 1869-1870; 17 leaves (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Judgment in a financial dispute in the entitled action Doña Trinidad Campos versus Don Nestor Garzon. Petition was initially pursued by Don Agapito Campos who died and the case was taken up by his widow.
  - Cuaderno que comprende la competencia de jurisdiccion iniciada por el C. Juez 2o [Segundo] de 1a [primera] instancia de la Capital de México para conocer en el juicio ejecutivo que sobre pesos sigue en este juzgado el C. Manuel Gonzales Barona, 1870; 11 leaves (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Evidence in support of an executive judgment in a financial dispute in the entitled action Manuel Gonzales Barona versus Luís Barragan. At issue is the lack of compliance with a monetary judgment found in favor of Manuel Gonzales Barona against Luís Barragan.
  - Juicio de hacienda publica sobre introduccion fraudulenta de los barriles de aguardiente, 1870; 10 leaves (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Judgment regarding the seizure of illegal barrels of brandy found at the business of José María Lopez and Juan Vinay. Lopez confessed to running liquor at his house without proper permits. Lopez also implicated Martin Gallegos.
  - Nombramiento de curador hecho por los menores Manuel y María Antonia Guerrero en favor de D[on] Manuel Marquez Oviedo, 1870; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Documents in support of the naming of Don Manuel Marquez Oviedo as guardian for the minor children of decedent José María Guerrero: Manuel and María Antonia Guerrero, ages fourteen and twelve respectively.
  - Autos de la testamentaría de D[on] Patricio Martinez de Oropeza, 1866-1870; 15 leaves (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Probate documents pertaining to the estate of Don Patricio Martinez de Oropeza. Will and testament reveals Doña Antonia García de Oropeza, widow, and the couple's children José Cornelio, Demetrio Dario, and Angel Francisco Oropeza as heirs.
  - [Dispute over a drawn draft between Don Juan Rueda, Don Ramon Rueda y Tijera and Don Antonio Gayol], 1869-1871; 54 leaves (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Documents pertaining to a disputed account draft by Juan Rueda containing an endorsement which read: "Paid to the order of the [Got?] Society and the Santiago Mill Company in the value of one thousand, eight-hundred and seventy."
  - Juicio verbal sobre p[eso]s, El abogado representante de D[o]n Enrique Pontal contra D[o]n Antonio Gayol, 1868-1873; 112 leaves (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Folder includes petitions, correspondence, and other legal documents in a civil suit initiated by Enrique Pontal against Antonio Gayol, a Spanish subject, over a disputed lien. Don Antonio Gayol protested the allegation that he owed payments to Don Enrique
  - Acta de tranzacion entre los herederos de la testamentaría de J[uan] Ant[oni]o Gonzalez, 1870; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Probate documents including the last will and testament for Juan Antonio Gonzalez. Petition requests payment of estate expenditures with the remainder to be divided by the following adult heirs: María Dolores Gonzales, Yldefonso Gregorio
  - Ejecutivo sobre p[eso]s promovido por D[on] Ygnacio Moreno Leon contra D[on] Manuel Gonzalez Madrid, Concluído, 1867-1870; 9 leaves (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Petiton and legal documents pertaining to a final judgment in a dispute over a rental agreement in the entitled action Don Ygnacio Moreno Leon versus Don Manuel Gonzalez Madrid. File contains a rental agreement for the property Hacienda de San José.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pago de honorarios promovido por el C. D[octo]r Manuel Limon contra el C. Juan García, 1870; 8 leaves (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Petition by Dr. Manuel LimÓn against Don Juan García for fees and expenses relating to an operation performed by Dr. LimÓn for Don García's daughter.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos, D[on] Gabino Gonzales contra D[oñ]a Dolores Sebilla, 1870-1871; 20 leaves (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Civil suit over money in the entitled action Don Gabino Gonzales versus Doña Dolores Sevilla over payments owed by Doña Sevilla. File includes a petition by Don Gabino Gonzales against Doña Dolores Sevilla for interest and legal costs.
  - Autos de la tercería de preferencia interpuesta por D[on] Rafael Cortez en el juicio ejecutivo que sigue D[on] Tomas Urrutia contra D[on] Mariano Molina sobre p[eso]s, 1868-1871; 13 leaves (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Arbitration documents for preference interposed by Don Rafael Cortez in the executive judgment which follows in Don Tomas Urrutia versus Don Mariano Molina, over money.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos, El representante del C. Mariano Martinez contra el Síndico del H. Ayuntamiento de esta Municipalidad, 1870-1872; 8 leaves (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Verbal judgment in a financial dispute between Mariano Martinez versus the trustee for the city council of Santa María.
  - Ejecutivo sobre pesos promovido por Doña María Luz Arriola contra el S[eñor] Felipe Gomez, 1867-1870; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Civil suit initiated by Doña María Luz Arriola versus Señor Felipe Gomez for debts owed.
  - Juicio verbal promovido sobre pesos por D[on] Manuel Fellez contra D[on] Antonio Várgas, 1869-1870; 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Verbal judgment in a financial dispute in Don Manuel Fellez versus Don Antonio Várgas.
  - Diligencias practicadas á solicitud del súbdito Aleman José Senecal pidiendo la entrega de una fábrica de cerveza que prestÓ á Luís Sedra, 1870; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Petition in a civil suit initiated by German subject, José Senecal, demanding the return of beer brewing materials which were found in the possession of Luís Sedra, also a German subject.
  - Juicio ejecutivo promovido sobre pesos por el S[eñ]or Lic. D[on] José María Carvajal contra D[on] Pedro Montes, 1870; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Executive judgment awarding money in the entitled action Manuel Gonzalez Barona versus Pedro Montes.
  - Testimonio de las diligencias practicadas en la tercería de dominio que promoviÓ la Señora D[oñ]a Petra Oliva de Moreno en el juicio que sobre pesos intentÓ en su contra Don José Vicente Moreno, 1870-1871; 11 leaves (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Testimony of diligence by Señora Doña Petra Oliva de Moreno in a civil arbitration for a financial dispute against Don José Vicente Moreno. File includes petitions, witness information, and interrogatory responses.
  - Juicio verbal Adolfo Rosin contra José Soledad Aycardo sobre pesos, Concluído, 1870; 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Verbal judgment in a civil suit by Adolfo Rosin, an American citizen, versus José Soledad Aycardo. File includes an accounting of debts owed by José Soledad Aycardo and the judgment appears to have been satisfied.
  - Juicio ejecutivo sobre pesos El C. Lic. José María Carvajal por D[on] Fran[cis]co Ponce contra el C. Mariano Vera Gomez, 1871; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Executive judgment over money in a civil matter entitled Don Francisco Ponce versus Mariano Vera Gomez.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos, El abogado representante del C. Manuel Gonzales Barona contra el curador de los menores hijos de Don Manuel Lira, 1852-1871; 22 leaves (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Verbal judgment for money in a civil suit by Manuel Gonzales Barona versus the guardian of minor children, Miguel and Petronilo Lira, heirs of the estate of Don Manuel Lira. File includes interrogatories in the entitled matter and the disputed account.
  - Ocurso presentado por los menores Doña Francisca, Doña Vicenta y Doña Andrea Piñeiro nombrando tutor y curador a Don Antonio España de esta vecindad, 1870-1871; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Petition on behalf of minors Doña Francisca, Doña Vicenta and Doña Andrea Piñeiro naming Don Antonio España guardian ad litem.
  - [Documents pertaining to the estate of Don José Benito Campos who died intestate], 1871-1872; 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Petition by creditor Francisco Cabrera, contesting the intestacy of José Benito Campos. Petitioner asks for satisfaction of outstanding debts. The court mandates that the a notice be published in the newspaper for 30 days by the estate.
  - [Account draft paid to the order of Don Mariano Ponce], 1870-1871; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Account draft in the amount of $1,100 silver pesos made payable to Don Mariano Ponce authorized by Don Mariano Bera Gomez. Account draft was subsequently endorsed by Don Mariano Ponce to Don Manuel Linarte.
  - [Petition by Manuel Linarte outlining an agreement for repayment of a loan borrowed by Mariano Vera Gomez], 1871; 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Petition reflecting that Mariano Vera Gomez fulfilled his obligation to repay Manuel Linarte.
  - Acta del juicio verbal sobre demanda de pesos, entablada por D[on] Felipe San Vicente contra D[on] Antonio Aramburo administrador de la hacienda del Sebadal, 1871; 5 leaves (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Act for verbal judgment regarding a demand for money entered by Felipe San Vicente versus Antonio Arumbaro, administrator for the Sebadal property. Petitioner Don Felipe San Vicente demanded that Don Antonio Aramburo repay an outstanding lien.
  - Promovido por Macedonia Mejia de Cruz tutora de sus hijos, pidiendo se les declare herederos al intestato [sic] de Luís Cruz, 1871; 13 leaves (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Petition by Macedonia Mejía de Cruz on behalf of her children, José Manuel, María Juana Amparo, José Ernesto de los Angeles, and José Maria, seeking that they be declared legal heirs to the estate of Luís Cruz who died intestate.
  - Juicio civil sobre pesos, D[on] Jesus Alfaro contra D[on] Luís Ramirez, 1871; 5 leaves (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Civil judgment for money in the entitled action Don Jesus Alfaro versus defendant Don Luís Ramirez. File includes a balance sheet of money owed by Luís Ramirez.
  - Juicio verbal sobre p[eso]s, El S[eñor] Lic. José M[ar]ía Carvajal contra el S[eñor] TeÓfilo Vera, 1870-1871; 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Verbal judgment for money in an action against TeÓfilo Vera. File includes petition and legal documents. Teofilo Vera contested a court judgment found against him. A subsequent note on the petition by attorney José M[ar]ía Carvajal is included.
  - Doña Carlota Got solicitando la separacion de gananciales en su matrimonio, 1871; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Petition by Doña Garlota Got requesting a separation of marital property. Petition indicates that Francisco Got and Carlota Ravard were married in France in 1840 in accordance with the civil laws of that country and those of the Catholic church.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos. El representante de D[on] Jesus Alfaro contra D[on] Antonio Pérez Arroyo, 1871-1872; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Verbal judgment for money in the entitled matter of Don Jesus Alfaro versus Don Antonio Pérez Arroyo. File includes a letter acknowledging receipt of payment for legal costs for José María Carvajal, Don Jesus Alfaro's legal representative.
  - Autos del intestado de D[on] José Guadalupe Várgas que se siguen en el juzgado de 1a [primera] instancia del Distrito y p[o]r ante el Escrib[ian]o Armino, 1871; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Notification to the court of José Guadalupe Várgas's death. Várgas died intestate and left behind a widow, María Ygnacia Alva. Documents include a petition by Jesus Várgas concerning outstanding claims to the estate.
  - Promovido por D[o]n José Haro sobre el pago de 390 pesos 15 centavos que le adeuda el intestado de Luís Cruz, 1871; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Petition for payment of a debt owed to Don José Haro, a merchant, by the estate of Luís Cruz who died intestate. Case documents include a balance sheet and petitions.
  - Juicio civil ejecutivo sobre pesos promovido por D[on] Mariano Ponce contra D[on] Ygnacio Moreno Leon, Concluído, 1871; 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Executive civil judgment for money in the entitled action Don Mariano Ponce versus Don Ygnacio Moreno Leon.
  - D[on] Joaq[ui]n Soto contra D[on] Andres Várgas sobre injurias, 1871; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Civil suit by Don Joaquin Soto, alderman of Tenango, versus Don Andres Várgas for injuries caused by Andres Várgas's libel. Among the injuries listed by Don Joaquin Soto is an allegation that Don Andres Várgas said that Joaquin Soto stole mules.
  - [Legal documents pertaining to the sale of property in Santiago by the guardians of Refugio and Vicente Ruis to Jesus Alfaro], 1871; 6 leaves (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Petition lists Carmen García and Anastacio Ruis as guardians of Refugio and Vicente Ruis.
  - Civil promovido por el abogado representante de D[oñ]a María de Jesus Soto pidiendo que D[o]n MÓnica Aguilar ministre las litisexpensas para continuar el juicio de divorcio que en su contra tiene promovido, 1870-1871; 36 leaves (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Petition pertaining to litigation costs in a civil suit for divorce between Doña María de Jesus Soto and Don MÓnica Aguilar.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos contra los ciudadanos Rafaél Duran y Antonio Armador, 1868-1870; 7 leaves (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Verbal judgment in a financial dispute between residents Rafaél Duran and Antonio Armador.
  - [Petition filed by the judicial receiver for San Luís ironworks following a restraining order obtained by Señora Lenora (Ortiz de Castellá), representative of the estate of Don José Castellá in a civil suit against Morthier and Pazos Society], 1871; 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - [Petition by Doña María de Jesus Soto de Aguilar to enforce a judgment for alimony or spousal support against Señor MÓnico Aguilar], 1873; 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - El juicio verbal sobre pesos seguido por el Subdito Español D. M. R. B. [Don Martin Rodriguez Baez] contra la Señora Doña Joséfa García de Ruiz, 1872-1873; 11 leaves (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Petitions, interrogatories, and other legal documents pertaining to a judgment in the entitled action Don Martin Rodriguez Baez, a Spanish subject, versus Doña Joséfa García de Ruiz. The case also references a financial dispute against Juan Bengoa.
  - [Probate documents for the estate of Doña Luisa Vera], 1872-1873; 19 leaves (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Legal document certifying the death of Doña Luisa Vera, 39 years of age who died of a pulmonary condition and left behind her children Don Ygnacio Veras and Doña [María] Guadalupe [F]osado. Petition by Doña María Guadalupe [F]osado contesting.
  - El Señor Haro solicitando se levante la intervenio de unos efectos de su propiedad, 1872-1873; 35 leaves (Box 6, Folder 2)
    File contains two separate civil suits involving José Haro, a Spanish merchant. The first as entitled involves pertains to a dispute with La Sociedad Mercantil Meneces y Gonzales. The second case is a mercantile dispute involving Don Martin Rodriguez.
  - [Probate documents for Albino Pérez], 1872; 5 leaves (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Interrogatory responses by the estate auditor, a document certifying the death of Albino Pérez, who died intestate, and petition by Ysabel Salgado, decedent's widow, protesting the intestacy of Albino Pérez on behalf of their four minor children.
  - Juicio civil, Ejecutivo sobre pesos: El abogado representan de D[oñ]a Ramona Vergara de Ponce contra D[o]n Mariano Vera Gomez, 1867-1873; 146 leaves (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Executive civil judgment in a lengthy financial dispute in the entitled action, Doña Ramona Vergara de Ponce versus Don Mariano Vera Gomez. Documents reflect the existence of a mortgage obligation for Hacienda de Otontepec granted by Mariano Vera Gomez.
  - El C. Manuel Gonzales Barona como albacea testamentaría de un finada esposa la S[eño]ra D[o]ña Catalina García solicitando licencia p[ar]a la venta de ganados y semillas, 1872-1873; 22 leaves (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Probate documents for the estate of Señora Doña Catalina García. Includes petitions and legal documents submitted by Manuel Gonzales Barona, decedent's husband and executor of her estate. Barona sought a license for the sale of livestock and seed.
  - Juicio verbal promovido por el C. Rafael Arroyo contra D[oñ]a Maura Torre, sobre entrega de Cien pesos, valor de una casa y varios objetos, de la propiedad del primero., 1872; 15 leaves (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Verbal judgment furthered by Rafael Arroyo versus Doña Maura Torre for the entry of $100 pesos, value of a house and various objects, the property of Rafael Arroyo.
  - Don Francisco del Puerto contra el C. Mariano Vera Gomez sobre pesos, 1872-1873; 13 leaves (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Civil suit for money in the entitled action Don Francisco del Puerto versus Mariano Vera Gomez.
  - El Sr. D[o]n José Antonio Martinez contra D[o]n José Panfilo Gomez sobre p[eso]s, 1870-1872; 7 leaves (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Civil suit for money in the entitled action José Antonio Martinez versus José Panfilo Gomez.
  - Intestado del C. Martin Gallegos, 1872; 6 leaves (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Documents pertaining to the intestacy of Martin Gallegos including a legal death notification for decedent who died of a tubercolosis-related complication and left behind a widow, Lorenzas Peralta.
  - Poder especial otorgado por Doña María Joséfa Margarita Franco en favor del C. Licenciado Gabriel Ormaechea, 1872; 7 leaves (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Probate documents for the estate of Felipe Franco. Petition indicates that María Joséfa Margarita Franco was the natural daughter of Felipe Franco and Guadalupe Hernandez, who were unmarried. María Franco sought to preserve her rights as heir.
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos, promovido por el Súbdito Español Don Martin Rodriguez Baz, contra la Señora Doña Joséfa García de Ruiz, 1872; 21 leaves (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Verbal judgment for money furthered by Don Martin Rodriguez Baz, a Spanish subject and merchant, versus Señora Doña Joséfa García de Ruíz. In dispute were commercial and contractual issues between the two parties involving the store "La Mexicana."
  - Juicio sumario sobre alimentos intendado p[o]r Lorenza Baños contra el C. Francisco Ramirez, 1872; 17 leaves (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Summary judgment for child support requested by Lorenza Baños from Francisco Ramirez. Petitioner Lorenza Baños indicated that she was the mistress of Francisco Ramirez, that they lived together for several years, and had minor children José Manuel Marcia
  - Juicio verbal sobre pesos, El C. Cristobal Arriola contra el de igual clase Antonio Guzman, 1869-1872; 17 leaves (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Verbal judgment for money in a civil action entitled CristÓbal Arriola versus Antonio Guzmán, of the same class. File includes petitions and legal documents, a balance sheet of legal fees and expenses incurred by CristÓbal Arriola, and a legal agreement.
  - Tercería interpuesta por el representante del C. Ricardo Limon sobre la propiedad de un caballo embargada a Candelario Alfaro en el juicio verbal que sobre pesos en su contra Matias Frejo, 1870-1872; 5 leaves (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Mediation proposed by the representative of José Ricardo LimÓn regarding the disputed ownership of a horse seized from Candelario Alfaro who had a verbal judgment found against him in a civil suit for money initiated by Matias Frejo. File includes a sign.
  - Acta del juicio verbal sobre pesos, Los C. C. Vicente Hernandez y Fran[cis]co Ortiz, 1871-1872; 7 leaves (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Act for verbal judgment over money in a civil matter involving debts owed by decedent José María Ortiz. According to petition and witness statements, Francisco Ortiz was the brother of decedent José María Ortiz and was allegedly responsibility for his brother.
  - El Subdito Espanol D[o]n Ant[oni]o Gayol con la S[eño]ra Castellá sobre pesos, 1872-1873; 22 leaves (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Legal documents and petitions in a civil suit for money involving Don Antonio Gayol, a Spanish subject, and Señora TeÓfila Ortiz de Castellá, a widow.
  - Acta del juicio verbal sobre p[eso]s. El representante de la sociedad Got y C[ompañi]a ... contra D[o]n Antonio Gayol, 1871-1872; 7 leaves (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Act for verbal judgment for money in the entitled matter Got Society and Company versus Don Antonio Gayol. File includes an account draft entered into evidence, a balance sheet outlining legal fees and court costs, and petitions.
  - [Petition requesting verbal judgment for money in a civil matter between Manuel Arroyo on behalf of José Luciano Moñtano and Don Sanchez Hidalgo, as executor for Don Luís Calla], 1872; 2 leaves (Box 6, Folder 18)